Schulz, Joan; Papers apap216
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Joan Schultz Papers
ca. 1968-1980
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Joan Schultz
apap216
1.4 cubic ft.
The collection includes materials related to the women's issues with a particular emphasis on the University at Albany, SUNY. Records of particular interest are those of the Equal Employment Opportunity Advisory Committee, Capital District Women, and the Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Joan Schultz and Judith Fetterley.
Biographical History
Joan Schultz was one of the founders of the Department of Women's Studies at the University at Albany, SUNY. She taught courses in American literature and women's studies at the university.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes materials related to the women's issues with a particular emphasis on the University at Albany, SUNY. Records of particular interest are those of the Equal Employment Opportunity Advisory Committee, Capital District Women, and the Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY.
Related collections include Andrea Lurie (APAP-051), Judith Fetterley (APAP-085), Gloria DeSole (APAP-215), and the Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, Albany Chapter (UA-089). Additional related collections can be found at the subject pages for Women and Education.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series.
Women; Albany, New York; Women’s rights--New York (State); Women--Employment--New York (State); Universities and colleges--New York (State)--Faculty; Schulz, Joan; State University of New York at Albany; Caucus on Women’s Rights at SUNY. Albany Chapter
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, ca. 1970-1972 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 1)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Adisory Committee, 1970-1975 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 2)
- Association of American Colleges, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 3)
- Affirmative Action, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 4)
- Boyer Meeting, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 5)
- Charters and Proclamations, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 6)
- Conferences and Conference News, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 7)
- Conference Stuff, Motions from Judy, etc., etc., Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 8)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, Miscellaneous Notes and Minutes, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 9)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, Newsletters, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 10)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 11)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, 1971 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 12)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, Albany, 1972 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 13)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, 1973 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 14)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, 1974 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 15)
- Caucus on Women's Rights at SUNY, 1975 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 16)
- Day Care, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 17)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Committee, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 18)
- Fellowships, Grants, Training Programs, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 19)
- The Feminist Press, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 20)
- Full Status-Reduced Load, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 21)
- I.F. Stone Weekly, 1968-1970 (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 22)
- Insurance Policies, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 23)
- Job Data, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 24)
- Concerns Job Vacancies, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 25)
- Legislate Reports, Government Findings, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 26)
- Capital District Women, Mimeo Masters, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 27)
- MLA Women's Caucus, Undated (Box 1 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous News Clippings and Essays, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 1)
- Names of All Kinds, Directories, ca. 1970s (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 2)
- NOW, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 3)
- Ewald B. Nyquist, News Clipping, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 4)
- Part-time Materials, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 5)
- Salary Charts and Information, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 6)
- Retirement and Pension Plans, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 7)
- Special Budget Proposals, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 8)
- The Spokeswoman, 1972 (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 9)
- Title IX, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 10)
- United University Professions, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 11)
- Women in Administrative Positions, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 12)
- Women's Newsletters, Assorted, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 13)
- Women's Political Caucus, New York State Conference, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 14)
- Work Force Analysis, Undated (Box 2 (Joan Schultz Papers), Folder 15)